pcrepairshop.org 2016-03-18

# Privacy Policy at The PC Repair Shop

This Application collects some Personal Data from its Users.

## Data Controller and Owner

The PC Repair Shop,  
webadmin@pcrepairshop.org  

## Types of Data collected

Among the types of Personal Data that this Application collects, by itself or through third parties, there are: Cookies, Usage data, geographic position and email address. 

Other Personal Data collected may be described in other sections of this privacy policy or by dedicated explanation text contextually with the Data collection.  
The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application.  
Any use of Cookies - or of other tracking tools - by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.  
Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services.

Users are responsible for any Personal Data of third parties obtained, published or shared through this Application and confirm that they have the third party's consent to provide the Data to the Owner.

## Mode and place of processing the Data

### Methods of processing

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.  
The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

### Place

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

### Retention time

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

## The use of the collected Data

The Data concerning the User is collected to allow the Owner to provide its services, as well as for the following purposes: Commercial affiliation, Traffic optimization and distribution, Interaction with external social networks and platforms, Geolocation, Analytics, Managing contacts and sending messages, Handling payments, Interaction with support and feedback platforms, Content commenting, RSS feed management and Displaying content from external platforms. 

The Personal Data used for each purpose is outlined in the specific sections of this document.

## Detailed information on the processing of Personal Data

Personal Data is collected for the following purposes and using the following services:

  * ### Analytics

The services contained in this section enable the Owner to monitor and analyze web traffic and can be used to keep track of User behavior.

#### Google Analytics (Google Inc.)

Google Analytics is a web analysis service provided by Google Inc. (“Google”). Google utilizes the Data collected to track and examine the use of this Application, to prepare reports on its activities and share them with other Google services.  
Google may use the Data collected to contextualize and personalize the ads of its own advertising network.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/) – [Opt Out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en)

#### Quantcast Measure (Quantcast Corporation)

Quantcast Measure is an analytics service provided by Quantcast Corporation.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.quantcast.com/privacy)

#### Wordpress Stats (Automattic Inc.)

Wordpress Stats is an analytics service provided by Automattic Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://automattic.com/privacy/)

  * ### Commercial affiliation

This type of services allows this Application to display advertisements for third party products or services. Ads can be displayed either as advertising links or as banners using various kinds of graphics.  
Clicks on the icon or banner posted on the Application are tracked by the third-party services listed below, and are shared with this Application.  
For details of which data are collected, please refer to the privacy policy of each service.

#### Amazon Affiliation (Amazon)

Amazon Affiliation is a commercial affiliation service provided by Amazon.com Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.amazon.com/gp/help/customer/display.html/ref=hp_rel_topic?ie=UTF8&nodeId=468496)

  * ### Content commenting

Content commenting services allow Users to make and publish their comments on the contents of this Application.  
Depending on the settings chosen by the Owner, Users may also leave anonymous comments. If there is an email address among the Personal Data provided by the User, it may be used to send notifications of comments on the same content. Users are responsible for the content of their own comments.  
If a content commenting service provided by third parties is installed, it may still collect web traffic data for the pages where the comment service is installed, even when users do not use the content commenting service.

#### Disqus (Disqus)

Disqus is a content commenting service provided by Big Heads Labs Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies, Usage data and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/466259-privacy-policy) – [Opt out](https://help.disqus.com/customer/portal/articles/1657951)

  * ### Displaying content from external platforms

This type of services allows you to view content hosted on external platforms directly from the pages of this Application and interact with them.  
This type of service might still collect web traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### YouTube video widget (Google Inc.)

YouTube is a video content visualization service provided by Google Inc. that allows this Application to incorporate content of this kind on its pages.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.it/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

  * ### Geolocation

#### Geolocation (This Application)

This Application may collect, use, and share User location Data in order to provide location-based services.  
Most browsers and devices provide tools to opt out from this feature by default. If explicit authorization has been provided, the User’s location data may be tracked by this Application.

Personal Data collected: geographic position. 

  * ### Handling payments

Payment processing services enable this Application to process payments by credit card, bank transfer or other means. To ensure greater security, this Application shares only the information necessary to execute the transaction with the financial intermediaries handling the transaction.  
Some of these services may also enable the sending of timed messages to the User, such as emails containing invoices or notifications concerning the payment.

#### PayPal (PayPal Inc.)

PayPal is a payment service provided by PayPal Inc., which allows Users to make online payments using their PayPal credentials.

Personal Data collected: various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

  * ### Interaction with external social networks and platforms

This type of services allow interaction with social networks or other external platforms directly from the pages of this Application.  
The interaction and information obtained through this Application are always subject to the User’s privacy settings for each social network.  
This type of service might still collect traffic data for the pages where the service is installed, even when Users do not use it.

#### Facebook Like button and social widgets (Facebook, Inc.)

The Facebook Like button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Facebook social network provided by Facebook, Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.facebook.com/privacy/explanation)

#### Google+ +1 button and social widgets (Google Inc.)

The Google+ +1 button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Google+ social network provided by Google Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.google.com/intl/policies/privacy/)

#### LinkedIn button and social widgets (LinkedIn Corporation)

The LinkedIn button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the LinkedIn social network provided by LinkedIn Corporation.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy)

#### Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets (Pinterest)

The Pinterest “Pin it” button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Pinterest platform provided by Pinterest Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://about.pinterest.com/en/privacy-policy)

#### Twitter Tweet button and social widgets (Twitter)

The Twitter Tweet button and social widgets are services allowing interaction with the Twitter social network provided by Twitter Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://twitter.com/privacy)

  * ### Interaction with support and feedback platforms

This type of services allows Users to interact with third party support and feedback platforms directly from the pages of this Application.  
If one of these services is installed, it may collect browsing and Usage Data in the pages where it is installed, even if the Users do not actively use the service.

#### Uservoice Widget (Uservoice Inc.)

The Uservoice Widget is a service for interacting with the Uservoice support and feedback platform provided by Uservoice Inc.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.uservoice.com/privacy/)

  * ### Managing contacts and sending messages

This type of services makes it possible to manage a database of email contacts, phone contacts or any other contact information to communicate with the User.  
These services may also collect data concerning the date and time when the message was viewed by the User, as well as when the User interacted with it, such as by clicking on links included in the message.

#### MailChimp (The Rocket Science Group, LLC.)

MailChimp is an email address management and message sending service provided by The Rocket Science Group, LLC.

Personal Data collected: email address. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/)

  * ### RSS feed management

This type of services allows this Application to manage RSS feeds and the distribution of their content. Depending on the characteristics of the service used, these services may be used to insert ads within the content and to gather statistics data from them.

#### Feedburner (Google)

Feedburner is a service to manage RSS feeds provided by Google Inc. It allows the collection of statistics on what content is consumed and to insert ads in it.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and Usage data. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/)

  * ### Traffic optimization and distribution

This type of services allows this Application to distribute their content using servers located across different countries and to optimize their performance.  
Which Personal Data are processed depends on the characteristics and the way these services are implemented. Their function is to filter communications between this Application and the User's browser.  
Considering the widespread distribution of this system, it is difficult to determine the locations to which the contents that may contain Personal Information User are transferred.

#### CloudFlare (Cloudflare)

CloudFlare is a traffic optimization and distribution service provided by CloudFlare Inc.  
The way CloudFlare is integrated means that it filters all the traffic through this Application, i.e., communication between this Application and the User's browser, while also allowing analytical data from this Application to be collected.

Personal Data collected: Cookies and various types of Data as specified in the privacy policy of the service. 

Place of processing: US – [Privacy Policy](https://www.cloudflare.com/security-policy/)

## Cookie Policy

This Application uses Cookies. To learn more and for a detailed cookie notice, you may consult the [Cookie Policy](http://www.iubenda.com/privacy-policy/446216/cookie-policy "Cookie Policy").

## Additional information about Data collection and processing

### Legal action

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services.  
The User declares to be aware that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities. 

### Additional information about User's Personal Data

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request. 

### System Logs and Maintenance

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address). 

### Information not contained in this policy

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document. 

### The rights of Users

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above. 

This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies. 

### Changes to this privacy policy

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request that the Data Controller removes the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users. 

### Information about this privacy policy

The Data Controller is responsible for this privacy policy, prepared starting from the modules provided by Iubenda and hosted on Iubenda's servers. 

###  Definitions and legal references 

#### Personal Data (or Data)

Any information regarding a natural person, a legal person, an institution or an association, which is, or can be, identified, even indirectly, by reference to any other information, including a personal identification number.

#### Usage Data

Information collected automatically from this Application (or third party services employed in this Application), which can include: the IP addresses or domain names of the computers utilized by the Users who use this Application, the URI addresses (Uniform Resource Identifier), the time of the request, the method utilized to submit the request to the server, the size of the file received in response, the numerical code indicating the status of the server's answer (successful outcome, error, etc.), the country of origin, the features of the browser and the operating system utilized by the User, the various time details per visit (e.g., the time spent on each page within the Application) and the details about the path followed within the Application with special reference to the sequence of pages visited, and other parameters about the device operating system and/or the User's IT environment.

#### User

The individual using this Application, which must coincide with or be authorized by the Data Subject, to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Subject

The legal or natural person to whom the Personal Data refers.

#### Data Processor (or Data Supervisor)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization authorized by the Data Controller to process the Personal Data in compliance with this privacy policy.

#### Data Controller (or Owner)

The natural person, legal person, public administration or any other body, association or organization with the right, also jointly with another Data Controller, to make decisions regarding the purposes, and the methods of processing of Personal Data and the means used, including the security measures concerning the operation and use of this Application. The Data Controller, unless otherwise specified, is the Owner of this Application.

#### This Application

The hardware or software tool by which the Personal Data of the User is collected.

#### Cookies

Small piece of data stored in the User's device.

* * *

#### Legal information

Notice to European Users: this privacy statement has been prepared in fulfillment of the obligations under Art. 10 of EC Directive n. 95/46/EC, and under the provisions of Directive 2002/58/EC, as revised by Directive 2009/136/EC, on the subject of Cookies.

This privacy policy relates solely to this Application.

Latest update: December 19, 2015
